nationalww2museum.org 2018-09-03

# Privacy Policy | The National WWII Museum | New Orleans

The National WWII Museum is committed to protecting the privacy of its users and any personal information that they may share with us or that we hold. We value our users’ trust and recognize that maintaining this trust requires us to be transparent and accountable at all times. The Privacy Policy describes important information about the steps necessary to safeguarding all personal information about our users. The personal information provided by the user will be used to fulfill the services requested by them, and, if you additionally consented to it, market to you through our email program.  Personal information in our possession is maintained and used in ways that respect individual privacy. Employees are educated about the importance of protecting personal information and consumer privacy, and only authorized employees are officially granted access to personal information.

The National WWII Museum collects two types of information from users who visit our website: anonymous information that is automatically collected from all visitors to our site and personal information knowingly and voluntarily provided by the user. 

**Use and Disclosure of Anonymous Information  **

If you do not fill out any forms and simply read pages or download information from our site, certain information about your visit is stored automatically. We use this information to optimize our site experience and make the site more useful to you. The information does not identify you personally. This information is collected through the Google Analytics platform using small files of information stored on your computer’s hard drive by your web browser known as cookies. 

We collect the following types of information:

  * The domain name and IP address of the computer from which you accessed our website
  * Aggregate information about which pages consumers access or visit
  * The browser type and operating system used to access the website
  * Geographic location from which you accessed our website
  * Time and date information for when you accessed our website
  * Number of pages visited during a session
  * Referral link used to access our website

**Use and Disclosure of Personal Information**

The National WWII Museum only collects personal information that you voluntarily provide to us. This information is collected from sources such as event registration, member sign up, donation forms, and surveys. Personal information that may be collected includes your name, postal address, and e-mail address. The Museum uses and discloses personal information only for certain purposes that are identified to the user. We may use it to establish and manage our relationship with a user, as well as providing requested information. Personal information can also help us understand users and identify preferences and expectations. We collect user information for internal use only, and just to the extent required for our purposes. We obtain relevant personal information about users lawfully and fairly.

The Museum collects personal information when you:

  * Purchase a ticket to the Museum, BB’s Stage Door Canteen, PT-305 or any other paid Museum event online
  * Register to attend a free Museum event
  * Register for our e-mail list
  * Complete a Donation Form
  * Join or Renew your Charter or Patriots Circle Membership
  * Make a Tribute Gift or send a Gift Membership
  * Send an e-mail to any member of The National WWII Museum staff
  * Fill out a survey
  * Purchase items from our Museum Store

The National WWII Museum will not disclose personal information collected from users to private third parties unless the law requires such disclosure.

This information is used to improve the scope and content of the Museum’s services on the Internet, and, in some cases, to respond to you. 

If you decide to give us personal information for a particular purpose, we may contact you about other programs or opportunities with The National WWII Museum. You will always have an immediate opportunity to decline further communication.

**Sharing or Selling of Personal Information**

The Museum will not share donor or customer e-mail addresses to third parties. The Museum may exchange donor postal mailing lists with other organizations for a single use. An organization that receives the Museum’s mailing list must agree to strict parameters which limit the use of the data. For example:

  1. The names and mailing addresses will only be used for a specific project;
  2. The Museum must approve the contents of the mailing piece before it is sent to the members of our list;
  3. The data file containing the mailing list will not be forwarded to any other person or entity except when necessary to complete the specific project;
  4. No copies of any type of the data file will be made by the receiving organization; and
  5. The data file of the names and addresses will be returned or destroyed when the project is completed.

We do use third-party processors to process data on our behalf. These service providers support The National WWII Museum in hosting and operating websites, marketing, and analytics. External, third-party data processing is governed by the privacy policies of these third-party providers.

**Cookies**

We collect information through the use of cookies. Cookies are short simple text files of information classified in two ways: 1. “long-term” or “persistent” are stored on your computer’s hard drive and 2. “session” cookies are temporarily stored to your computer’s Random Access Memory. “Session cookies” are used to keep track of and store information so the user does not have to supply the information multiple times. These cookies expre when your session on our Museum website ends. “Long-term cookies” enable us to measure if users return to the website for multiple visits. These cookies contain no personal information and will only be used in aggregate form. The information that is collected through cookies at this site is handled in the same manner as other information collected here. You can configure your web browser to refuse cookies or to notify you when a website attempts to send you a cookie. You can also check your hard drive for cookie files and delete them from your computer. Credit card information cannot be accessed using cookies.

**Email Correspondence**

If you have voluntarily given us your email address, we will use your data to contact you or send promotional emails relating to your interests and or Museum events and mission-based initiatives and campaigns. In addition, we may use email tracking technology to know whether emails are opened or shared links have been accessed. You may remove your consent anytime by clicking on an unsubscribe link or emailing info@nationalww2museum.org directly. 

E-mail messages will be treated the same as any other written communication. They may be subject to public inspection or legal disclosure. Please do not put confidential and personal information such as social security number, date of birth, bank account and credit card information, mother's maiden name or medical information in your non-secure e-mail communications to The National WWII Museum. Your privacy cannot be protected or insured by The National WWII Museum during email or unsecured web form transmission.

Any personally identifying information which you choose to provide (for example, your mailing address) in an electronic mail message or web form requesting information, any comments on policies or issues, or other information collected in this manner, is used solely for information and, in some cases, to respond to you. An e-mail automatically includes your email address and certain routing information, including your internet server.

**Online Purchases, Donations and Catalog Requests**

If you make an online purchase, online donation or request a catalog, we may also collect your e-mail and/or your mailing address to contact you for marketing purposes. We may share the mailing addresses we collect with other reputable publishers to help them contact consumers for marketing purposes.

The personal information we collect is stored on a secured server. We use industry-standard encryption technologies to prevent your personal and financial information from being seen as it travels to our servers. We routinely evaluate and upgrade our security measures.

**Information Correct & Opt Out**

If you believe the information we have about you is incorrect, you are welcome to contact us so we can update it and keep your data accurate. 

If you do not want to receive e-mail from The National WWII Museum in the future, or do not want us to share your mailing address with other publishers, please let us know by e-mailing us at info@nationalww2museum.org or by sending a letter to:

The National WWII Museum  
945 Magazine Street  
New Orleans, LA 70130

Please provide your exact name and address and tell us if you want your name removed from our mailing list, the list we may share with other companies, or both.

**Links to Other Websites**

This website has links to other websites. These include links to websites operated by other governmental agencies, nonprofit organizations and private businesses. Many of these sites may operate under different privacy standards. Visitors to those websites are advised to review the privacy statements of those sites. The National WWII Museum is not responsible for any content on a linked site.

**Rights and Contact Information**

You may request information as to the use and storage of your personal information and revoke consent of use at any time. Please direct these requests and/comments in writing to [interactive@nationalww2museum.org](mailto:interactive@nationalww2museum.org) or mail to:

The National WWII Museum  
945 Magazine Street  
New Orleans, LA 70130
